Guide to the Patti Hirahara Collection 1955-2020
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Patti Hirahara collection
1955-2020
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 https://libraries.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
SC 014.7
Hirahara, Patti
11.56 Linear feet of shelf space 22 Boxes, 1 Oversize flat folder
The Patti Hirahara Collection consists primarily of newspapers and magazine articles pertaining to the collection of photographs taken by her father, Frank, and her grandfather George Hirahara. The collection also contains materials about Patti and general information about the Hirahara family.
Patti Hirahara was born in California in 1955 to Frank and Mary Hirahara. Patti grew up in Anaheim, California and graduated from California State University, Fullerton with a Bachelor of Arts in Communications in 1977. Hirahara runs Productions by Hirahara, a public relations and television production firm. Her career in public relations and marketing includes extensive work with the Japan External Trade Organization (JETRO). Hirahara has also produced works in television and print media. In November 2010, Patti donated to Washington State University the first installment of what was to become the George and Frank C. Hirahara Photograph Collection of Heart Mountain, Wyoming.
The Patti Hirahara Collection contains newspapers pertaining to her family, her father’s and grandfather’s photographs of Heart Mountain Relocation Center, and the incarceration of Japanese Americans during World War II. The newspapers are mainly from California and Seattle but there are several from the Northwest Region. Issues of the Rafu Shimpo and the North American post comprise the bulk of the collection.
Within the collection Ms. Hirahara has noted several articles that reference the George and Frank C. Hirahara Collection and specific items within the collection. Reference to material from the Hirahara Collection include photographs contained in Manuscripts Archives and Special Collections, exhibits featuring the Hirahara Collection, and the programs for the stage musical Allegience, which gives thanks for the use of photograph for the set design, and for the Los Angeles Area Emmy Awards. A documentary titled Witness: The Legacy of Heart Mountain won 3 Los Angeles Area Emmys and was co-produced and written by David Ono. The collection also includes 2 photocopies containing maps for incarceration centers, which were euphemistically called “Relocation Centers”.
The materials in this collection are arranged chronologically. Within the chronological arrangement, materials are arranged alphabetically by title.
This collection is open and available for research use.
The Patti Hirahara Collection was donated to Washington State University by Patti Hirahara 2014 (MS.2014.28), 2015 (MS.2015.08, MS.2015.10), 2017 (MS.2017.23), and 2021 (MS.2021.09).
George and Frank C. Hirahara Photograph Collection of Heart Mountain, Wyoming, 1932-2016 (SC 014)
Tom T. Hide Collection, 1925-2012 (SC 014.1)
Okubara Family Collection, circa 1943-2008 (SC 014.2)
Takeda Family Collection, 1938-circa 2012 (SC 014.3)
Kenneth Nishiyori Collection, 1942-1944 (SC 014.4)
George and Doris McIntyre Papers, 1944-1945 (SC 014.5)
Mari Tsuruyama Okumura Collection, 1936-2014 (SC 014.6)
Terry Ishihara Collection, 1989-2012 (SC 014.8)
Mike Mackey Collection, 1940-2002 (SC 014.9)
Heart Mountain High School Tempo, 1945 (SC 014.10)
Fusataro Nakaya Photographs, circa 1944 (SC 014.11)
Nabata Family Collection of Heart Mountain Photographs, circa 1942-1945 (SC 014.12)
Frank Chin Oral History Collection, 1974-1986 (Cage 654)
Inez Puckett McEwen Collection on Japanese-American Incarceration, 1942-1943 (Cage 4923)
Japanese American Redress Collection, 1976-2000 (Cage 5126)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Hirahara, Patti -- Archives
Washington State University -- History
Japanese Americans -- Forced removal and internment, 1942-1945; Japanese Americans -- Washington (State) -- History; Black-and-white photography -- Social aspects -- United States -- History -- 20th century
Japanese Americans; Washington (State); Photographs
- Patti Hirahara Profile, 1955-2011 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Oregon Camera Club information, 1959-2011 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Hirahara Photograph Collection references and publicity, 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- The Orange County Register, 2011 April 29/2012 October 23 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- The Lewiston Tribune, 2011 July (Box 2, Folder 6)
- International Examiner, 2011 July 20-August 02 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- The Asian Reporter, 2011 August (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Heart mountain Interpretive Learning Center (commemerative edition), 2011 August (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Anaheim Bulletin, 2011 September (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Billings Gazette, 2011 September (Box 2, Folder 11)
- The Daily Evergreen, 2011 September (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Kamai Forum, 2011 September (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Moscow-Pullman Daily News, 2011 September (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Pacific Citizen, 2011 October 07/2011 November 03 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2011 October 08/2012 July 12 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Pacific Citizen, 2011 November 04-December 15 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Yakima Herald republic, 2011 October (Box 2, Folder 18)
- The North American Post, 2012 Janurary (Box 2, Folder 19)
- The North American Post, 2012 Feburary (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Pacific Citizen, 2012 Feburary 03-March 01 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- The North American Post, 2012 March (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Pacific Citizen, 2012 March 02-April 05 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- The North American Post, 2012 April (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Pacific Citizen, 2012 April 06-May 03 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- The North American Post, 2012 May (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Pacific Citizen, 2012 May 04-May 31 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- The North American Post, 2012 June (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Pacific Citizen, 2012 June 01-July 05 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Los Angeles Times, 2012 June 13-October 23 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- The North American Post, 2012 June (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Pacific Citizen, 2012 July 06-19 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- The North American Post, 2012 August (Box 3, Folder 33)
- The North American Post, 2012 September (Box 3, Folder 34)
- 11th Annual Evening Aloha Gala Dinner, 2012 October (Box 3, Folder 35)
- The North American Post, 2012 October (Box 3, Folder 36)
- The North American Post, 2012 November (Box 3, Folder 37)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2012 November (Box 3, Folder 38)
- The North American Post, 2012 December (Box 3, Folder 39)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2012 December (Box 3, Folder 0)
- The North American Post, 2013 January (Box 4, Folder 42)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2013 January (Box 4, Folder 43)
- The North American Post, 2013 Febuary (Box 4, Folder 44)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2013 Febuary (Box 4, Folder 0)
- The North American Post, 2013 March (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Pacific Citizen, 2013 March 15-April 04 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2013 March (Box 4, Folder 0)
- The North American Post, 2013 April (Box 5, Folder 51)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2013 April (Box 5, Folder 0)
- The North American Post, 2013 May (Box 5, Folder 54)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2013 May (Box 5, Folder 0)
- The North American Post, 2013 June (Box 5, Folder 57)
- The Rafu Shimpo (1 of 2), 2013 June (Box 5, Folder 58)
- The Rafu Shimpo (2 of 2), 2013 June (Box 6, Folder 59)
- The North American Post, 2013 July (Box 6, Folder 60)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2013 July (Box 6, Folder 0)
- The North American Post, 2013 August (Box 6, Folder 63)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2013 August (Box 6, Folder 0)
- The North American Post, 2013 September (Box 7, Folder 66)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2013 September (Box 7, Folder 0)
- The North American Post, 2013 October (Box 7, Folder 69)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2013 October (Box 7, Folder 0)
- The North American Post, 2013 November (Box 7, Folder 72)
- The Rafu Shimpo (1 of 2), 2013 November (Box 7, Folder 73)
- The Rafu Shimpo (2 of 2), 2013 November (Box 8, Folder 74)
- The North American Post, 2013 December (Box 8, Folder 75)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2013 December (Box 8, Folder 0)
- The North American Post, 2014 January (Box 8, Folder 78)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2014 January (Box 8, Folder 0)
- The North American Post, 2014 Feburary (Box 9, Folder 81)
- Pacific Citizen, 2014 Feburary 07-20 (Box 9, Folder 82)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2014 Feburary (Box 9, Folder 0)
- The North American Post, 2014 March (Box 9, Folder 85)
- Pacific Citizen, 2014 March 07-20 (Box 9, Folder 86)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2014 March (Box 9, Folder 0)
- The North American Post, 2014 April (Box 9, Folder 89)
- Pacific Citizen, 2014 April 18-May 01 (Box 9, Folder 90)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2014 April (Box 9, Folder 0)
- Asian Reporter, 2014 May (Box 10, Folder 93)
- The North American Post, 2014 May (Box 10, Folder 94)
- Pacific Citizen, 2014 May 02-15 (Box 10, Folder 95)
- Portland Magazine, 2014 May (Box 10, Folder 96)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2014 May (Box 10, Folder 0)
- The North American Post, 2014 June (Box 10, Folder 99)
- Pacific Citizen, 2014 June 06-19 (Box 10, Folder 100)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2014 June (Box 11, Folder 0)
- North American Post, 2014 July (Box 11, Folder 103)
- Pacific Citizen, 2014 July 04-August 07 (Box 11, Folder 104)
- The Rafu Shimpo, 2014 July (Box 11, Folder 0)
- Asian Reporter, 2014 July (Box 11, Folder 107)
- North American Post, 2014 August (Box 12, Folder 108)
- Pacific Citizen, 2014 August 08-21 (Box 12, Folder 109)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2014 August (Box 12, Folder 0)
- Daily Evergreen, 2014 September (Box 12, Folder 112)
- North American Post, 2014 September (Box 12, Folder 113)
- Pacific Citizen, 2014 September 05-18 (Box 12, Folder 114)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2014 September (Box 12, Folder 115)
- Asian Reporter, 2014 October (Box 12, Folder 116)
- North American Post, 2014 October (Box 12, Folder 117)
- Pacific Citizen, 2014 October 03-Novemeber 13 (Box 13, Folder 118)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2014 October (Box 13, Folder 0)
- North American Post, 2014 November (Box 13, Folder 121)
- Pacific Citizen, 2014 November 14-December 11 (Box 13, Folder 122)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2014 November (Box 13, Folder 0)
- Newsletters and mailers, 2014 (Box 14, Folder 125)
- Yakima Valley Museum NEH grant, 2014 (Box 14, Folder 126)
- Witness DVD and Emmy Award program, 2014 (Box 14, Folder 127)
- Washington State University Magazine Winter, 2014-2015 (Box 14, Folder 128)
- Allegiance Musical Program, 2012 September (Box 14, Folder 129)
- Programs and Publications, 2013-2015 (Box 14, Folder 130)
- Katherine McCartney correspondence, 2014-2015 (Box 14, Folder 131)
- Asian Pacific America interview, 2015 (Box 14, Folder 132)
- Robert Tsuneo Endo memorial file, 2015 (Box 14, Folder 133)
- Postcards of Wakayama Prefecture, undated (Box 14, Folder 134)
- The North American Post, 2011 December (Box 14, Folder 135)
- The Asian Reporter, 2012 January (Box 14, Folder 136)
- Nichi Bei, 2014 December (Box 14, Folder 137)
- Pacific Citizen, 2014 December 12-2015 January 22 (Box 14, Folder 138)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2014 December (Box 14, Folder 139)
- Nichi Bei, 2015 January (Box 14, Folder 140)
- The North American Post, 2015 January (Box 15, Folder 141)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2015 January (Box 15, Folder 0)
- Pacific Citizen, 2015 January 23- February 05 (Box 15, Folder 144)
- NA Post, 2015 February (Box 15, Folder 145)
- Nichi Bei, 2015 March (Box 15, Folder 146)
- The North American Post, 2015 March (Box 15, Folder 147)
- Pacific Citizen, 2015 March 06 -April 02 (Box 15, Folder 148)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2015 March (Box 15, Folder 149)
- The Daily Evergreen, 2015 April (Box 16, Folder 150)
- Japanese Daily Sun, 2015 April (Box 16, Folder 151)
- Nichi Bei, 2015 April (Box 16, Folder 152)
- The North American Post, 2015 April (Box 16, Folder 153)
- Pacific Citizen, 2015 April 03-30 (Box 16, Folder 154)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2015 April (Box 16, Folder 155)
- Nichi Bei, 2015 May (Box 16, Folder 156)
- The North American Post, 2015 May (Box 16, Folder 157)
- Pacific Citizen, 2015 May 15-June 04 (Box 16, Folder 158)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2015 May (Box 16, Folder 159)
- The North American Post, 2015 June (Box 17, Folder 160)
- Pacific Citizen, 2015 June 05-18 (Box 17, Folder 161)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2015 June (Box 17, Folder 162)
- Japan Connection, 2015 July (Box 17, Folder 163)
- Nichi Bei, 2015 July (Box 17, Folder 164)
- The North American Post, 2015 July (Box 17, Folder 165)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2015 July (Box 17, Folder 166)
- Japan Connection, 2015 August (Box 17, Folder 167)
- Nichi Bei, 2015 August (Box 17, Folder 168)
- The North American Post, 2015 August (Box 17, Folder 169)
- Pacific Citizen, 2015 August 07-September 03 (Box 17, Folder 170)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2015 August (Box 18, Folder 171)
- Nichi Bei, 2015 September (Box 18, Folder 172)
- The North American Post, 2015 September (Box 18, Folder 173)
- Pacific Citizen, 2015 September 04-October 01 (Box 18, Folder 174)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2015 September (Box 18, Folder 175)
- The North American Post, 2015 October (Box 19, Folder 176)
- Pacific Citizen, 2015 October 16-November 12 (Box 19, Folder 177)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2015 October (Box 19, Folder 178)
- Anaheim Press, 2015 November (Box 19, Folder 179)
- Gardena Valley News, 2015 November (Box 19, Folder 180)
- Nichi Bei, 2015 November (Box 19, Folder 181)
- The North American Post, 2015 November (Box 19, Folder 182)
- Pacific Citizen, 2015 November 13-December 10 (Box 19, Folder 183)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2015 November (Box 19, Folder 184)
- The North American Post, 2015 December (Box 19, Folder 185)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2016 January (Box 20, Folder 186)
- New York magazines, 2016 February (Box 20, Folder 187)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2016 March (Box 20, Folder 188)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2016 April (Box 20, Folder 189)
- Pacific Citizen, 2016 May 06-19 (Box 20, Folder 190)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2016 May (Box 20, Folder 191)
- Newspapers, 2016 June (Box 20, Folder 192)
- Events featuring Hirahara Images, 2016 (Box 20, Folder 193)
- Promotional Packet for Legacy of Heart Mountain Screening, 2015 (Box 20, Folder 194)
- Buddhist Temple of Chicago, 2016-2017 (Box 20, Folder 195)
- Pacific Citizen, 2020 February 21-March 05 (Box 20, Folder 196)
- Pacific Citizen, 2020 October 23-November 05 (Box 20, Folder 197)
- Pacific Citizen, 2020 November 20-December 17 (Box 20, Folder 198)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2020 February 13 (Box 20, Folder 199)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2020 October 22 (Box 20, Folder 200)
- Rafu Shimpo, 2020 November 28 (Box 20, Folder 201)
- Family ephemera including Heart Mountain DVD/mounted photograph of Frank Hirahara graduating Washington State University, plaque facsimile of Frank Hirahara's diploma/awards received by Patti Hirahara, 1948-2006 (Box 21)
- Los Angeles Times, 2015 April (Box OS, Folder 1)
- Anaheim Bulletin, Orange County Register, Los Angeles Times, 2015 October-November (Box OS, Folder 2)
- Films of Remembrance display, 2015 (Box OS, Folder 3)
- Moscow-Pullman Daily News, 2014 November 20 (Box OS, Folder 4)
- Moscow-Pullman Daily News, 2014 December 19 (Box OS, Folder 4)
- Photograph of David Ono and Jeff MacIntyre holding Emmy awards, 2014 (Box OS, Folder 5)
- Anaheim Bulletin, 2014 October 30 (Box OS, Folder 6)
- Inland 360, 2014 October 09-15 (Box OS, Folder 6)
- Los Angeles Register, Los Angeles Times, Orange County Register, 2014 May (Box OS, Folder 7)
- Portland Tribune, 2014 Feburary (Box OS, Folder 8)
- Front Line, 2014 March- August (Box OS, Folder 9)